GRAHAM A. SCHMIDT

38 Day St. Apt 30, Somerville, MA, 02144 Phone: (516) 672-4855 schmidtg@gmail.com http://www.schmidtg.com

"I'm smart, reliable and get things done."

Full Stack Web Developer: Over 10+ years experience in web development, graphic design and team leadership. I often earn a "go-to" role for teams that I join. I'm constantly self-learning and challenging myself everyday to be the most effective software engineer. I take pride in delivering results, and I communicate proactively to ensure that expectations are met regularly.

RELEVANT SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- **Specialties**: PHP, MySQL, Javascript/Ajax, jQuery, HTML/CSS, Git, MVC, Internet technologies
- Passion for developing seemless User experiences that leverage innovative web technologies
- Formal training in both graphic design and computer science
- Dedicated and hard-working individual who delivers polished results every time
- Highly self-motivated and constantly looking to make things better

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Back-end Engineer

Hungry Fish Media, LLC / NutraClick

September 2011 – Present

- Write, maintain and optimize PHP scripts to handle automation and management of large datasets
- Lead developer for Magento Enterprise e-commerce site (www.healthexperts.com)
- Built various support tools for handling management of 15,000+ SKU catalog
- Shared lead development (Zend) for building self-serve 'Membership' site of 30,000+ users
- Earned greater responsibility for independently managing the completion of major projects

Senior Front-End Engineer

September 2010 – 2011

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Built numerous business tools and reports using the Flourish PHP framework, AJAX, and custom javascript namespaced objects
- Rigorously tested and improved landing pages on a daily basis using an in-house analytics A/B testing platform along with Google Analytics
- Refactored existing codebase to be more object-oriented for greater code reuse
- Crafted hand-coded pages (VIM, Chrome Dev, Firebug) in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript for superior readability, rapid development and ease of maintenance
- Progressed to senior front-end developer after only 6 months in the front-end role, and coordinated the hiring of new team members and taking on senior duties

Graphic Designer

September 2009 – September 2010

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Regularly created numerous Landing Pages and web advertisements for display on large websites such as MSN.com, Yahoo.com, and AOL which generated some of the highest click-thru rates and lead acquisitions in the company's history
- Created a successful landing page in one work day that went on to become the fastest growing lead acquisition website by the company
- Created various print, promotional and packaging materials that helped establish one of the top selling nutritional sports supplement brands in GNC stores nationwide

[September 2008 – September 2009 travelled throughout India, Nepal, NZ, Africa]

Web Developer and Graphic Designer

January 2007 - August 2008

Bedlam Paintball / Nationwide Paintball (Edinburgh, Scotland)

- Co-ordinated a successful delivery of a £30k+ project to deliver an Oracle-based online booking system in which massive company data and services relied upon
- Further developed an existing PHP-based booking system which enabled Sales agents to save 30 minutes of administrative work and greatly improve their efficiency
- Created attractive competition-based landing pages for Blockbuster movie promotions that collected thousands of sales leads and heavily contributed towards a turnover of £15-20k for those specific campaigns

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Concepts: UX/UI architecture, wireframing, Front-end engineering, MVC, AJAX, OOP, JSON, Singlepage Apps, Version control (Git), REST, Database design, Agile, Scrum, SEO, CMS, Big Data, Visualization, Web architecture, Functional programming

Software/IDEs: MacVim, Git, Sublime, Intellij IDEA, Emacs, Photoshop, Flash

Languages: PHP, Javascript, C, Java, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, XML, ReqEx, Actionscript

Databases/Servers: MySQL, MSSQL, Apache, Mac OS X

Frameworks/Libraries: Zend, Flourish (PHP), Codelgniter, Laravel, jQuery, jQuery mobile, Prototype,

YUI, Backbone.js, Underscore.js, Handlebars.js, Twitter Bootstrap, SASS

Platforms: Magento, Wordpress, Expression Engine, Drupal, Etomite/ModX

APIs: Google Maps, Magento, Paypal, Twitter, Litle

Testing Tools: Chrome Dev Tools, Firebug, New Relic, Selenium, Xdebug, JSLint, Google Analytics

RECENT PERSONAL PROJECT URLS

LexPress mobile app (PHP, JS, jQuery mobile) http://www.schmidtg.com/projects/nextlex Eventry.net registration system (Codeigniter) http://www.eventry.net/ CMAP LLC (Wordpress)

http://www.cmapllc.com/

EDUCATION

Graduate-Level Coursework

2011 - Present

Harvard University Extension School (Cambridge, MA)

Java for Distributed Computing, Data structures, Intensive Intro to CS (pre-reg)

Bsc Computer Science

Awarded 2005

University of Regina (Regina, Canada)

Software Engineering, Human Computer Interaction, Visualization, Databases

Multimedia Certificate

Awarded 2003

Applied Multimedia Centre (Regina, Canada)

• Graphic design, page layout, typography, sound editing, 3D animation

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- Fast learner and incredibly resourceful
- Excellent communication skills
- Able to manage time and resources efficiently
- Independent, reliable and very hard-working

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Adventure travel, cooking, hiking, homebrewing, bagpiping

REFERENCES

Available upon request